# Alerechi Ordu

#### Backend Developer

I am a software engineer specializing in backend applications. I create components and features on the server side, indirectly accessed by a user through a front-end application or system. My task is developing, maintaining, testing, and debugging the entire back end. CRUD



- alerechiordu@gmail.com
- Lagos, Nigeria
- twitter.com/Kingrechi

- +2348160251019
- in linkedin.com/in/alerechiordu
- github.com/Rechidesigns

### **EDUCATION**

### **Higher National Diploma (HND)** Lagos State Polytechnic

10/2019 - 02/2021

Courses

 Business Administration and Management

Lagos, Nigeria

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Backend Developer / Internship Univelcity

06/2022 - Present

Lagos, Nigeria

Team Collaboration /Software Research/Deployment

- Work with stakeholders and fellow developers.
- Design and implement Python code using the Django framework.
- Identify and fix bottlenecks that may arise from inefficient code, Identify and fix software bugs.
- Manage the security of the platform.
- Create a wide variety of unit tests to verify the functionality of software.
- Database administration and management using MYSQL.
- Proficient in object oriented programming (OOP). Knowledge of front end languages.
- Web Script development and write detailed documentation around the code.
- Designing Restful APIs with Django framework (DRF).
- Building and deploying scalable microservice architectures using Python.

Contact: Fashola Blessing -

+234(0)8063052539 | blessing@univelcity.com

# **ORGANIZATIONS**

Trinitas Foundation (01/2022 - Present)

Volunteer - Food Aid, Education, Empowerment

Mr Nigeria Republic (02/2021 - 02/2022)

Pageant King - Male TV Show, Fashion Shows, Runways, Pageantry

Family Health International 360 (01/2017 - 01/2018)

Counseling-HIV/AIDS Awareness, Maintenance & Examination

# **SKILLS**

MySQL

Problem Solving & Analytical skills

Django REST Framework / API

Designs / Wire framing / Prototyping

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### E-Commerce Web App

https://github.com/Rechidesigns/Python-Django/tree/main/today

#### Blog Web App

https://github.com/Rechidesigns/Python-Django/tree/main/blog

#### Job Posting Web App

https://github.com/Rechidesigns/Projects

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Univelcity (06/2022 - Present)

Backend Web-Development

Udemy (04/2022 - Present)

User Interface Design Essentials-UI/UX Design

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Best Male Dresser (01/2016 - 12/2017)

Departmental Ambassador / Mr. BAM

420 Men Apparel LLC. USA Louisiana (02/2019 - Present)

Brand Ambassador / Personal Assistant to the CEO

# **INTERESTS/HOBBIES**

Design **Tech-Events** 

Artifice Intelligence

cyber Security

Software Updates

Gospel Music

Entrepreneurship

Fashion

Black-Models

Fitness/Sports